ukflooringdirect.co.uk 2014-06-26

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | UK Flooring Direct

**About Us**

We are UK Flooring Direct Ltd, a company registered in England with registered number 05542003 whose registered office is at Key Park Zone1a, Bayton Road Industrial Estate, Exhall, Coventry, CV7 9EL(and we refer to ourselves as “we”, “us” or “our” in this document). We own and operate this “Website” (meaning the www.ukflooringdirect.co.uk website) on our own behalf.

**About This Privacy and Cookie Policy**

In this Privacy Policy, references to “ **you** ” means any person submitting any data to us or to this Website about himself or herself or about any other living individual in respect of any use of the Website or the products available through the Website (each being a “ **Product** ”).

When you use different aspects of the Website, we may ask you to supply us with various information about you or anyone whom you represent. This Privacy Policy sets out the way in which we may use such information.

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy (together with our “Terms of Use”, "Terms and Conditions" and any other documents referred to in them) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is UK Flooring Direct Ltd, and our registration number with the Information Commissioner’s Office is Z1146402.

**Contacting Us**

Questions, comments, requests or suggestions regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [customerservices@ukflooringdirect.co.uk](mailto:customerservices@ukflooringdirect.co.uk), please reference this policy in the email subject line.

**Your Privacy**

Your privacy is very important to us.  We shall therefore only use your name and other information which relates to you in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy.  We will only use your personal data in a way that is fair to you.  We will only collect information where it is necessary for us to do so and we will only collect information if it is relevant to our dealings with you.

We will only keep your information for as long as we are either required to by law or as is relevant for the purposes for which it was collected.

**Data That We Collect**

We may collect and process your personal data for processing your purchase of a Product on the Website. We may obtain the following information about you:

  1. your title, name, date of birth, address, email address, telephone numbers, username, password and such other contact details as we require. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use the Website. We may also store information relating to any Products that you purchase; and
  2. payment information provided by you, for example, on placing an order for a Product available on the Website. This may include credit or debit card or bank account details.

You always have a right to contact us to find out what data we hold about you (although we charge a fee of £10 for making this available). You always have a right to ask us to correct any incorrect data we hold about you and to ask us to block or delete data we hold about you.

**Why We Collect Your Personal Data**

We use the information collected for the purpose of fulfilling your order, in case we have any queries and for our record keeping. We may also use that data to prove payment for the Product and deliver the Product to you. We also use that data to inform you when a Product is about to be delivered.

We may pass your name and address on to a third party in order to make delivery of the Product to you (for example, to our courier or supplier).

We may also use your data in order to manage the Website, collect payment from you, detect fraud or Website abuses, send you information relevant to the Website or the Products and in case we have any queries.

We also need your email address and other contact details, in particular, for sending you information relating to the Website and the services we offer.  This includes (without limitation) the following:

  1. To allow you to go ahead and register for an account on the Website, which allows you to purchase Products.  This includes sending an email to you to confirm your details, to give you initial information about the service we offer, and to enable you to commence ordering Products.
  2. To respond to you over any queries you raise with us.
  3. To give you a link to enable you to have a password resent to you if you tell us or the Website that you have forgotten it.
  4. To record and track details of transactions you carry out through or via the Website and of the fulfilment of your orders.
  5. To collect details of your visits to the Website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, web blogs and other communication data, whether this is required for our own purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.
  6. To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you.
  7. To allow us or selected third parties and our suppliers to use your data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you. However, to the extent this goes beyond use for completing any transaction with you, we will always obtain your explicit consent before doing this.

We also need to use your contact details and other information for any aspect of the Website (including, but without limitation, providing customer support, preventing or investigating prohibited activity, enforcing the Terms and Conditions and Terms of Use and verifying information). 

We may maintain your user history (such as frequency of use, data accessed and detail of data accessed) for up to six years following purchase.

**Your Obligations As To Your Data**

You must only submit to us, or the Website, information which is accurate and not misleading and you must keep it up-to-date and inform us of changes. You may do this through your Account or by telephone on 0844 327 0000.  By submitting data in respect of you and anyone else, you must ensure that you have full authority and consent to supply us with that data on their behalf and you warrant to us that you have that authority.

**Third Parties and Links**

We will disclose your personal data (including details of your credit or debit card or bank account) to our suppliers should you wish to make an order for a product or service made available by that supplier.

We may pass your details to our agents and subcontractors to help us with any of our uses of your data set out in our Privacy Policy.  For example, we may use third parties to assist us with delivering products to you, to enable us to collect payments from you, to analyse data and to provide us with marketing or customer service assistance. 

We may exchange information with third parties for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

We may transfer your data to other companies in our group.

We may transfer our databases containing your personal information if we sell or may our business or part of it to an actual or potential purchaser.

We may also disclose your details as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

Other than as set out in this Privacy Policy, we shall NOT sell or disclose your personal data to third parties without obtaining your prior consent unless this is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy or unless we are required to do so by law.

**IP Addresses and Cookies**

We may obtain information about your general Internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer.

The Websites use cookies.  Cookies are tiny text files which identify your computer to our server as a unique user when you visit certain pages on the Websites and they are stored by your Internet browser on your computer's hard drive.  Cookies can be used to recognise your Internet Protocol address, saving you time while you are on, or want to enter, the Websites. 

We only use cookies for your convenience in using the Websites (for example to remember who you are when you want to amend your data without having to re-enter your email address and password) and not for obtaining or using any other information about you (for example targeted advertising). Your browser can be set to not accept cookies, but this would restrict your use of the Websites. 

Please accept our assurance that our use of cookies does not contain any personal or private details and are free from viruses.  If you want to find out more information about cookies, go to [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or to find out about removing them from your browser, go to[http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/index.html).

Please note that we collect data from the Websites about use of the Websites using a web analysis tool which uses cookies that are (able to be) used to generate pseudonyms for a user’s profile. This means that use cookies (which may be stored on your computer after you leave the Website) can store information about your visit.

Please also note that our suppliers and advertisers may also use cookies, over which we have no control. Here is a list of the main 3rd party cookies in use and their purpose.

**GCT  ** \- Conversion tracking to show us which keywords customers are using.

**aw2736** \- Set when you click on one of our links and used to let the advertiser and us know the website from which you came.

**AWSESS** \- Set when you see an advert and used to help us make sure we do not keep showing you the same ones.

**awpv2736** \- Set when you see an advert and used to let us know where you saw it.

**AW(flash cookie)** \- Set when you click on an Affiliate Window link and used to let us know the website from which you came.

**_aw_m_2736** \- Set when you click on an Affiliate Window link and used to let us know the website from which you came.

**_utma, utmb, utmc, _utmz, utmx** \- These enable the function of Google Analytics.This information helps us to improve the website and your shopping experience, and to make our marketing campaigns more relevant.

**Cnb7_CVTKEY** \- This cookie helps identify when you revisit the site, so we can count the number of new visitors.

**Cnb7k_CVTSESSIONKEY** \- This cookie helps identify the length of time spent on our site and enables us to see if your session has timed out whilst navigating the site.

**sc.ASP.NET_SESSIONID** \- This is Session Cam, and data collected is used to improve our website by enabling us to find and fix errors by playing back a complete users session.

**sc.UserId** \- This allows Session Cam to identify unique users and is used in our reporting.

Visual Web Optimizer - This enables us to see where you have clicked on our site, so we can create a better user experience.

**Where We Store Your Personal Data**

We have in place appropriate technical and security measures to prevent unauthorised or unlawful access to or accidental loss of or destruction or damage to your information. 

We store your personal details on a secure server.  We use industry standard security and firewalls on our servers.  When we collect payment card details electronically, we use encryption by using “HSBC Secure” epayments section.  Whilst we are unable to guarantee 100% security, this makes it hard for a hacker to decrypt your details.

We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards in connection with the collection, storage and disclosure of your information.  Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose personal information to you.

You are responsible for protecting against unauthorised access to your password and to your computer.

**Security**

Any payment transactions will be encrypted using “HSBC Secure” epayments section in the payment information you provide to us to pass on to a third party to make an order for a product or service. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will take reasonable steps to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted over the Internet; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**Your Rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data to provide marketing information about Products or the Website. You can make changes to your privacy settings in your Account part of the Website. We will change what you receive within a reasonable time. However, changing your privacy settings may inhibit your ability to use the Website so we do not recommend that you do this. You can also telephone us on 0844 327 0000 to make these changes.

The Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of suppliers, partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of those websites, please note that those websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for those policies. Please check those privacy policies before you submit any personal data to those websites.

**Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time.  Any amended Privacy Policy will be posted on the Website.  The amended Privacy Policy will apply immediately for new users and 30 days (or such other timeframe as we say when posting) after first posting for all existing users.  Each time you enter the Website or order a Product, you agree that the Privacy Policy current at that time shall apply to all information which we hold about you.

**Consent**

By submitting data to us and using the Website, you consent to our use of your data and of anyone you represent in the manner set out in this Privacy Policy (as amended from time to time, as described above) and you are responsible for ensuring that you have authority to consent on behalf of anyone about whom you submit data to us.

You also consent to us (or third party advertisers working through our website) placing cookies on your hard drive. You can turn these off if you want, through the settings on your browser. See the “IP addresses and cookies” section above. Please note that we will not place cookies on your hard drive by which you can be personally identified; if we do, we will ask for more, further, specific consent from you.

Please note that you can revoke any consent you have given us under this policy at any time by contacting us on [customerservices@ukflooringdirect.co.uk](mailto:customerservices@ukflooringdirect.co.uk), and referencing this policy in the email subject line, using the body of the email to say what consent you are revoking.

**Version**

This Privacy Policy was most recently updated on 23 November 2012.
